century21.ca 2019-12-08

# CENTURY 21 CANADA LIMITED PARTNERSHIP PRIVACY POLICY

                          CENTURY 21 CANADA LIMITED PARTNERSHIP
                                          PRIVACY POLICY
 Century 21 Canada Limited Partnership (“CENTURY 21”) recognizes the importance of
 protecting the personal information of our Customers, our prospective customers, brokers and
 sales people with our franchisees and anyone else from whom we may collect personal
 information from time to time whether in the course of real estate transactions or otherwise.
 This Privacy Policy discloses the type of personal information we gather from or about you
 (“You”), how we may use it, how and to whom we may disclose it, your right to access your
 personal information which we have collected and your right to correct or change that
 information where You believe it may be inaccurate. At CENTURY 21 we hope to give You as
 much control about your personal information as possible.
 CENTURY 21 and its Franchisees
 As a franchisor, CENTURY 21 does not provide real estate broker services. Real estate broker
 services are provided exclusively by CENTURY 21 franchisees (“Franchisees”). Each
 Franchisee is an independently owned and operated real estate broker business. While
 CENTURY 21 has undertaken extensive measures to control and ensure the privacy and security
 of personal information collected by it, it does not own or control the operations of its
 Franchisees. Customers and prospective customers who have concerns about the treatment of
 their personal information by a Franchisee with which they are dealing are urged to contact that
 Franchisee directly. This Privacy Policy addresses personal information that CENTURY 21 has
 in its possession or control
 What We Mean By Personal Information?
 Personal information is any information in whatever form about an identifiable individual.
 However, it does not include:
 1.        your name or information which would enable us to contact You at your place of
           employment including your name, position name or title, business telephone number,
           business address, business email and business fax number;
 2.        personal information about You that is publicly available information such as information
           available from a public registry or contained in a telephone book;
 3.        aggregated information that cannot be associated with You as a specific individual; and
 4.        information which is not about a person but which is about a company, association or
           another organization.
 What Personal Information Does CENTURY 21 Collect?
 CENTURY 21 collects the following personal information:
 1.        personal information which You voluntarily provide to us when You visit a CENTURY
19506.79765.MEP.9136469.3

                                                      2
           21 office (a Franchisee’s office) or that is otherwise provided directly to CENTURY 21,
           such as by telephone, email, mail or fax;
 2.        photographic images of your property, descriptions of the property and its sale price for
           marketing purposes, but only where we have obtained your prior consent; and
 3.        personal information which You voluntarily provide to us when You visit our website
           (the “Website”), such as when You open an account or subscription or complete a
           contact request, and personal information relating to your use of the Website (in
           accordance with our more detailed Website Privacy Policy set out below).
 Except where permitted by law, CENTURY 21 collects, uses and discloses your personal
 information with your knowledge and consent and we will do so fairly and openly.
 How We Use Your Personal Information
 CENTURY 21 uses personal information for the following purposes:
 1.        to put You in touch with a broker or sales person with one of our Franchisees who
           may contact You to assist You with listing property for sale or purchasing property;
 2.        to assist the broker or sales person in finding appropriate property for You;
 3.        unless You choose to opt-out, CENTURY 21 may use information about your home in
           marketing material (we will not use your name), and may use your contact information to
           promote and market additional services, products and special offers from CENTURY 21;
           and
 4.        for the purposes relating to use of personal information collected on the Website set out
           below in our Website Privacy Policy.
 Why We Disclose Your Personal Information
 1.        CENTURY 21 may share personal information with third parties engaged to assist us in
           providing services or products to You or to carry out one or more of the purposes
           described above.         These service providers are prohibited from using personal
           information for any purpose other than to provide this assistance and are required to
           protect personal information disclosed to them by us and to comply with the general
           privacy principles described in this Privacy Policy. Note that CENTURY 21 retains a
           U.S. located service provider (including, for example, WhereToLive.com, Inc.) for
           certain services and the personal information provided to that U.S. based provider is
           subject to the laws of the jurisdiction in which it operates.
 2.        CENTURY 21 discloses personal information when it makes the personal information a
           person has provided online available to its Franchisees and their brokers and sales people.
 3.        CENTURY 21 may disclose personal information gathered on the Website for the
           purposes set out below in our Website Privacy Policy.
19506.79765.MEP.9136469.3

                                                   3
 CENTURY 21 reserves the right to collect, use and disclose other personal information without
 your knowledge or consent if we are required to do so or if we are allowed to by law.
 Consent
 Except where required or permitted to do so without your consent, CENTURY 21 only collects
 your personal information with your consent. In most cases, CENTURY 21 relies on express
 consent. However, where the purpose of the collection of personal information is obvious on its
 face, CENTURY 21 may rely on your implied or deemed consent.
 In some cases, such as using your personal information for marketing services to You,
 CENTURY 21 will rely on opt-out consent. (You will receive the information unless You advise
 us You do not wish to receive it.)
 CENTURY 21 only collects personal information where it is reasonably necessary to provide the
 service which You are seeking and which we have agreed to provide. We do not use deceptive
 or misleading practices to obtain your consent.
 CENTURY 21 does not require You to consent to the collection, use or disclosure of personal
 information as a condition of the supply of a service by us unless such collection, use or
 disclosure is required to fulfill the aforementioned purposes of collection.
 CENTURY 21 reserves the right to collect, use or disclose personal information in certain
 limited circumstances, without your knowledge and consent, where required or permitted by law.
 You may withdraw your consent to the collection, use and disclosure of personal information in
 connection with the services that You have requested from us at any time, subject to legal or
 contractual restrictions and reasonable notice. CENTURY 21 will inform You of the
 implications of withdrawing your consent. If You wish to withdraw your consent at any time,
 please contact CENTURY 21’s Privacy Officer (see below for contact information).
 Access To Your Personal Information
 You have the right to access your personal information in the possession or control of
 CENTURY 21 and to know how that personal information has been and is being used, and to
 whom it has been disclosed. CENTURY 21 reserves the right to refuse to comply with all or
 part of a request where we are required to or are permitted to refuse to do so by the provisions of
 applicable personal information protection legislation.
 Applications must be in writing and be sent to our Privacy Officer either by mail or email at the
 addresses set out below. Applications should have sufficient detail that allows us to identify You
 and the personal information You are requesting.
 You may ask to have errors or omissions in your personal information in our possession or
 control corrected. If we are satisfied that the correction is reasonably necessary, we will correct
 the personal information and notify anyone to whom we have provided the personal information
 in the previous 12 months of the correction. If we are not satisfied that the correction should be
 made, we will annotate the personal information under our control of the correction requested
19506.79765.MEP.9136469.3

                                                   4
 but not made.
 Requests for access and correction will usually be responded to within 30 calendar days of
 receiving the request unless we apply to the applicable Privacy Commissioner for an extension.
 We charge $25 plus $.25 per page for providing You with copies of your personal
 information. In the event that it will take an unusually long time to collect your personal
 information, we may charge an additional amount. In each case, we will give You a full quote
 before photocopying the personal information. There is no charge for correcting personal
 information.
 We will assist You with your request and will respond as accurately and completely as
 reasonably possible. Where we refuse all or part of your request, we will give You the
 reasons for the refusal and the applicable legislation on which we base our refusal; the name and
 contact information of someone within CENTURY 21 who can explain the basis for the refusal
 and of your right to apply to a Privacy Commissioner for review.
 How We Protect Personal Information
 CENTURY 21 makes reasonable efforts to ensure that Your personal information is protected
 against loss and unauthorized access, collection, use, disclosure, copying, modifying, disposal or
 similar risks. This protection applies in relation to personal information stored in both electronic
 and hard copy form and will vary depending on the sensitivity of the information.
 Access to non-public personal information is restricted to selected employees or representatives
 on a need-to-know basis. In addition, CENTURY 21 employs generally accepted information
 security techniques, such as firewalls and access control procedures in order to protect personal
 information against unauthorized access, collection, use, disclosure, copying, modifying,
 disposal or similar risk.
 Retention of Personal Information
 CENTURY 21 retains personal information for as long as necessary to fulfill the purpose(s) for
 which it was collected and to comply with applicable laws. Personal information which is
 collected and used to make a decision about You is retained for at least one year. Your consent to
 such purpose(s) remains valid after termination of CENTURY 21’s relationship with You.
 Changes to this Privacy Policy
 CENTURY 21 reserves the right to modify this Privacy Policy at any time without notice. The
 Privacy Policy distributed at any time or from-time-to time posted on the Website shall be
 deemed to be the Privacy Policy then in effect.
 Accountability
 CENTURY 21 is responsible for the personal information under its control, and we have
 designated a Privacy Officer who is responsible for our compliance with this Privacy Policy and
 with applicable laws. Other individuals within CENTURY 21 may be delegated to act on behalf
 of the Privacy Officer and CENTURY 21 will use appropriate means to provide a comparable
19506.79765.MEP.9136469.3

                                                   5
 level of protection while information is being processed by a third party.
 You may contact our Privacy Officer as follows:
  CENTURY 21 Canada Limited Partnership
  Attention:              Privacy Officer
  Address:                700-1199 West Pender Street
                          Vancouver, BC
                          Canada V6E 2R1
  Phone:                  (604) 606-2100
  Fax:                    (604) 606-2125
  Email:                  privacy@century21.ca
 Dispute Resolution
 If You are unhappy about the collection, use or disclosure of your personal information by
 CENTURY 21, we ask that You discuss the matter further with our Privacy Officer.
 If You are not satisfied with the response, You may make an application or complaint to the
 appropriate Privacy Commissioner.
 Note to Brokers and Sales People
 In order to promote the services of our Franchisees and their brokers and sales people,
 CENTURY 21 collects certain personal information about them, such as photographs and
 contact information, in a variety of ways, including through OnlineOffice registration. This
 information is disclosed by CENTURY 21 when it makes the information available for
 Customers to access on the Website or through other means by which CENTURY 21 promotes
 their services.
 Much of this information is business contact information, which is not subject to privacy law or
 this Privacy Policy. However, to the extent that such information is personal in nature,
 CENTURY 21 will collect, use and disclosure this information in accordance with this Privacy
 Policy (see above) and, where applicable, with our Website Privacy Policy.
19506.79765.MEP.9136469.3

                          CENTURY 21 CANADA LIMITED PARTNERSHIP
                                  WEBSITE PRIVACY POLICY
 The following addresses the personal information Century 21 Canada Limited Partnership
 (“CENTURY 21”) may collect about You during any interaction with our website (the
 “Website”).
 Your Acceptance of this Website Privacy Policy
 By using the Website, You signify your agreement with and acceptance of CENTURY 21’s
 Website Privacy Policy. If You do not accept this Website Privacy Policy, You must not access
 or use the Website.
 CENTURY 21 may, at any time, without notice or liability, revise this Website Privacy Policy
 by updating this posting. You should periodically revisit this posting to review any revisions to
 this Website Privacy Policy. If any revision is not acceptable to You, You must cease accessing
 and using the Website. If You continue to access or use the Website after any revisions are
 posted You will be deemed to have accepted those revisions.
 Types of Personal Information
 We receive two types of personal information from Customers who visit the Website: (1)
 personal information that Customers provide through registration or other communication on the
 Website; and (2) personal information CENTURY 21 gathers through aggregated tracking
 procedures, such as tallying the number of page views throughout the Website over a given
 period of time. The second type of personal information enables us to tailor the Website content
 to better meet the needs of our Customers. However, we assure You that CENTURY 21 will not
 disclose your personal information to third parties except as permitted by applicable law.
 CENTURY 21 and its Franchisees
 As a franchisor, CENTURY 21 does not provide real estate broker services. Real estate broker
 services are provided exclusively by CENTURY 21 franchisees (“Franchisees”). Each
 Franchisee is an independently owned and operated real estate broker business. Customers
 applying for services through the Website apply through a Franchisee, not through CENTURY
 21. While CENTURY 21 has undertaken extensive measures to control and ensure the privacy
 and security of personal information obtained through the Website, it does not own or control the
 operations of its Franchisees. Customers and prospective customers who have concerns about the
 treatment of their personal information by a Franchisee with which they are dealing are urged to
 contact that Franchisee directly.
 How Does CENTURY 21 Collect Personal Information?
 (a)       Registration: CENTURY 21 does not collect your personal information through the
           Website except when such personal information is provided to us on a voluntary basis.
           For example, CENTURY 21 will collect a user’s name, address, phone number and/or e-
19506.79765.MEP.9136469.3

                                                      2
           mail address and any additional details that a user chooses to provide if he or she
           completes the portion of the Website that requests that CENTURY 21 or one of the
           Franchisees contacts the user or the user registers for an account or subscription on the
           Website. If you choose not to provide your personal information, please note that certain
           services associated with the Website may not be available to You as they cannot be
           supplied without your personal information. The personal information gathered through
           the Website is governed by the foregoing Privacy Policy.
 (b)       Usage tracking:
           (i)      Use of IP Addresses: An IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to
                    your computer whenever You are surfing the Internet. Web servers automatically
                    identify your computer by its IP address.
                    CENTURY 21 and/or its affiliates collect IP addresses for the purposes of system
                    administration, to report aggregated information to our advertisers, and to audit
                    the use of the Website. When Customers request pages from the Website, our
                    servers log the requesting Customers’ IP addresses. Except where You participate
                    in any online transaction CENTURY 21 may offer from time to time, we
                    normally will not link IP addresses to anything personally identifiable, which
                    means that Customers’ sessions will be logged, but Customer identity remains
                    anonymous to us. We can and will use IP addresses to identify a Customer when
                    we feel it is necessary to enforce compliance with our rules or terms of service or
                    to protect our service, the Website, or any person, or where it is otherwise
                    permitted by law.
           (ii)     Use Of Cookies: Cookies are bits of information that a website transfers to
                    an individual’s hard drive for record-keeping purposes. Cookies make Web
                    surfing easier for You by saving your preferences while You visit the Website.
                    We never save passwords or credit card information in cookies. The use of
                    cookies is an industry standard, and, as such, You’ll encounter them at most
                    major websites.
                    By showing how and when Customers use the Website, cookies help us see which
                    areas are popular and which are not. Many improvements and updates to the
                    Website are based on data collected using cookies, such as the total number of
                    visitors and pages viewed in a given period of time. This kind of information is
                    most easily tracked using cookies.
                    CENTURY 21 and/or its affiliates and Franchisees have two primary uses for
                    its cookies. First, we use them to specify preferences. For example, Customers
                    can specify keywords across several categories or markets so You do not have to
                    tell us over and over again about the kinds of homes You are interested in
                    obtaining information about. Secondly, we use cookies to track Customer trends
                    and patterns. This helps us to better understand our Customers’ needs and to
                    improve areas of CENTURY 21 and/or its affiliates’ services that our Customers
                    may find valuable. Sometimes, information from cookies is attached to
19506.79765.MEP.9136469.3

                                                       3
                    messages sent to our Customer Service department.                 While all of these
                    situations depend on the use of a cookie, You always have the option of disabling
                    the receipt of cookies on your computer by adjusting the cookies setting in your
                    Web browser preferences.
                    Most browsers are initially set up to accept cookies. You can reset your Web
                    browser to either refuse all cookies or indicate when a cookie is being sent, with a
                    concurrent option to accept or receive the cookie. However, note that some of the
                    services offered on the Website will not function properly or may be considerably
                    slower if You refuse to receive cookies. For example, without cookies, You will
                    not be able to set personalized preferences. You might also encounter difficulties
                    participating in online transactions offered on the Website from time to time.
                    Occasionally, You may receive cookies from our advertisers. CENTURY 21
                    and/or its affiliates do not control these cookies. The use of advertising cookies
                    sent by third-party servers is standard in the Internet industry.
           (iii)    Other: CENTURY 21 automatically collects anonymous statistical information
                    regarding usage of the Website. For instance, the Website will recognize the type
                    of browser you are using (Netscape, Internet Explorer, Safari, etc.), the address of
                    the Internet Service Provider You are using, the site that linked You to the
                    Website, the pages You visit at the Website and similar information. None of this
                    information identifies You personally.
 With Whom Does CENTURY 21 Share Your Personal Information?
 As a general rule, CENTURY 21 will not disclose any of your personal information except when
 we have your permission or under special circumstances, such as when we believe in good faith
 that the law requires it or under other specified circumstances, including those described below:
 (a)       Business Partners & Sponsors: CENTURY 21 may disclose some or all your personal
           information to business partners or sponsors, but this use will be specifically described to
           You prior to either the collection or transfer of the personal information.             Many
           promotions offer opportunities to request additional information from sponsors. By
           requesting more information, You give CENTURY 21 permission to transfer your
           personal information to the sponsor so they can fulfill your request. In many instances,
           only your e-mail address will be shared with the sponsor. If we intend on sharing more
           personal information with the sponsor than your e-mail, You will be notified prior to the
           transfer.
 (b)       Third Party Data and Data in the Aggregate: From time to time, on the Website You may
           be offered the opportunity to receive material or special offers from third parties. If You
           opt to receive information from these third parties, CENTURY 21 will (with your
           permission) share your name and e-mail address with such third parties.                Under
           confidentiality agreements, CENTURY 21 may match Customer information with third
           party data. Also, CENTURY 21 may disclose aggregated Customer statistics (i.e., where
           we disclose a characteristic of our Customers as a group and not as individuals) in order
19506.79765.MEP.9136469.3

                                                      4
           to describe our services to prospective partners, advertisers, and other third parties, and
           for other lawful purposes.
 (c)       Service Providers: Information CENTURY 21 receives through the Website is provided
           to services providers retained by CENTURY 21 including Filogix Inc. and
           WheretoLive.com, Inc., in order to organize and distribute appropriate personal
           information to enable CENTURY 21 and its Franchisees to communicate with its
           Customers and to provide information about marketing initiatives that may be of interest
           to its Customers.
 (d)       Other: CENTURY 21 may disclose account information in special cases when we have
           reason to believe that disclosing this information is necessary to identify, contact or bring
           legal action against someone who may be violating CENTURY 21’s Terms of Use or
           may be causing (either intentionally or unintentionally) injury to or interference with
           CENTURY 21’s rights or property, other CENTURY 21 Customers, or anyone else that
           could be harmed by such activities. CENTURY 21 may disclose or access account
           information when we believe in good faith that the law requires it and for administrative
           and other purposes that we deem necessary to maintain, service, and improve our
           products and services. Note that to the extent that CENTURY 21 retains a U.S. located
           service provider (including, for example, WhereToLive.com, Inc.), the personal
           information in that service provider’s control or possession is subject to the laws of the
           jurisdiction in which it operates.
 How Can You Control the Use of Your Personal Information?
 In case You change your mind or some personal information changes (such as your zip code or
 e-mail address), we will endeavour to provide a way to correct, update or remove the personal
 information You give us. Additionally, to keep You in control of the communications directed
 to You, we offer Customers the opportunity to “opt out” of having personal information shared
 with parties outside of CENTURY 21 and/or its affiliated companies. If You wish, for
 any reason, to update your personal information or if You object to any use of your personal
 information described in this Website Privacy Policy, You may contact CENTURY 21’s Privacy
 Officer:
           CENTURY 21 Privacy Officer
           700-1199 West Pender Street
           Vancouver, BC
           Canada V6E 2R1
           Phone: (604) 606-2100
           Fax: (604) 606-2125
           Email: privacy@century21.ca
 What happens when You link to a Third Party Website?
 You should be aware that when You are on the Website You could be directed to other third
 party websites that are beyond our control. There may, from time to time, be links to other third
 party websites from the Website that take You outside our service areas. For example, if You
19506.79765.MEP.9136469.3

                                                  5
 “click” on a banner advertisement on the Website, the “click” typically takes You off the
 Website. These other sites may include websites of advertisers, sponsors and partners that may
 use CENTURY 21’s and/or its affiliates’ and/or its Franchisees’ logos as part of a co-branding
 agreement. These other websites may send their own cookies to Customers, or otherwise collect
 data or solicit information.
 CENTURY 21 and its affiliates and Franchisees do not control such third party websites, and,
 therefore, are not responsible for their content.        CENTURY 21’s and/or its affiliates’
 provision of hyperlinks to these websites does not imply any endorsement of the material on
 such websites or any association with their operators. This Website Privacy Policy does not
 extend to anything that is inherent in the operation of the Internet and which is beyond the
 control of CENTURY 21, its affiliates or its Franchisees.
 Please keep in mind that whenever You give out personal information online (for example, via
 message boards or chat lines), that personal information can be collected and used by people You
 do not know. While CENTURY 21, its affiliates and its Franchisees strive to protect their
 Customers’ personal information and privacy, we cannot guarantee the security of any personal
 information You disclose online and so You disclose such information at your own risk.
 Is your Personal Information Secure from Others using the CENTURY 21 Website?
 The importance of securing your personal information is of the utmost concern to us. We
 exercise great care in providing secure transmission of your information from your computer to
 our servers. Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100%
 secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your personal information, CENTURY 21 and its
 affiliates cannot promise or warrant the security of any personal information You transmit to us,
 including through the use of our online products or services. Any such transmission is done so at
 your own risk. Once we receive your transmission, CENTURY 21 uses industry standard efforts
 to safeguard the confidentiality of your personal information, such as firewalls and
 Secure Socket Layers. However, ironclad security does not yet exist on the Internet.
19506.79765.MEP.9136469.3
